<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swift on Thoughtful Texts</title>
    <link>https://sadmansamee.github.io/categories/swift/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Swift on Thoughtful Texts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sadmansamee.github.io/categories/swift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(How to) Be an Intermediate iOS dev in 2021</title>
      <link>https://sadmansamee.github.io/how_to_be_intermediate_ios_dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sadmansamee.github.io/how_to_be_intermediate_ios_dev/</guid>
      <description>A beginner or associate level needs to know just to do something but to become an intermediate level you need to be able to do a certain thing in a certain way following best practices. I tried to list some of the things that an intermediate iOS dev should know about.
SwiftUI and Combine SwiftUI and Combine is the latest and most exciting thing in Apple Development ecosystem, these are excellent frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Caching Library, written in Swift that can cache Anything.</title>
      <link>https://sadmansamee.github.io/cachy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sadmansamee.github.io/cachy/</guid>
      <description>Needed a cache Library that has
 Asynchronous data downloading and caching. Asynchronous image downloading, caching and showing. Expiry date/time for all the objects individually. Multiple-layer hybrid cache for both memory and disk. Fine control on cache behavior. Customizable expiration date and size limit. Force refresh if needed. Independent components. Use the Cachy or CachyLoader system separately as you need. Can save JSON, UIImage, ZIP or anything. View extensions for UIImageView.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with WebRTC</title>
      <link>https://sadmansamee.github.io/webrtc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sadmansamee.github.io/webrtc/</guid>
      <description>Anybody who worked with WebRTC will agree that there is a huge lack of learning resources and on top of that on every few years, WebRTC standards changes and changes are big sometimes that makes previous resources outdated, creating more gap.
 WebRTC is a free, open project that provides browsers and mobile applications with Real-Time Communications (RTC) capabilities via simple APIs. The WebRTC components have been optimized to best serve this purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep your iOS projects healthy</title>
      <link>https://sadmansamee.github.io/keep_ios_projects_healthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sadmansamee.github.io/keep_ios_projects_healthy/</guid>
      <description>Keeping your code and projects is the best thing you can do to your projects and here’s how to do it your iOS projects written in swift.
Following style guide There are several style guide for writing swift, and every team member should follow them well. Such as
 Raywinderlich style guide Linkedin style guide Google style guide  Using tools In reality not everyone does it properly so there should be a way to enforce it amongst team members, a way of doing is manual code review which is very time-consuming and code review should happen in logic level not how a developer should declare variable or indentation, we could simple automate these things and invest our time more on harder things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
